Beyond the Walls: In Search of the Celts is a
documentary film directed by David Starkey.
Historian Dr Eleanor Barraclough travels through some of Britain's most beautiful landscapes to
reveal the true story of the mysterious British tribes often called the Celts.
Self - Presenter, played by Eleanor Barraclough.
Italy, officially the Italian Republic, is a
country in Southern and Western Europe.
It consists of a peninsula that extends into the Mediterranean Sea, with the Alps on its
northern land border, as well as nearly 800 islands, notably Sicily and Sardinia.
Italy shares land borders with France to the west; Switzerland and Austria to the north;
Slovenia to the east; and the two enclaves of Vatican City and San Marino.
It is the tenth-largest country in Europe by area, covering 301,340 km2 (116,350 sq mi), and the
third-most populous member state of the European Union, with nearly 59 million inhabitants.
Italy's capital and largest city is Rome; other major cities include Milan,
Naples, Turin, Palermo, Bologna, Florence, Genoa, and Venice.
The history of Italy goes back to numerous Italic peoples – notably including the ancient Romans, who conquered the
Mediterranean world during the Roman Republic and ruled it for centuries during the Roman Empire.
With the spread of Christianity, Rome became the seat
of the Catholic Church and the Papacy.
Barbarian invasions and other factors led to the decline and fall of the Western
Roman Empire between late antiquity and the Early Middle Ages.
By the 11th century, Italian city-states and maritime republics expanded, bringing renewed
prosperity through commerce and laying the groundwork for modern capitalism.
The Italian Renaissance flourished during the 15th and 16th
centuries and spread to the rest of Europe.
Italian explorers discovered new routes to the Far East and the New
World, contributing significantly to the Age of Discovery.
After centuries of political and territorial divisions, the Kingdom of Italy was established
in 1861, following wars of independence and the Expedition of the Thousand.
From the late 19th to the early 20th century, Italy industrialised and acquired a colonial empire, while the
south remained largely impoverished, fuelling a large immigrant diaspora to the Americas.
From 1915 to 1918, Italy took part in World War I with
the Entente against the Central Powers.
In 1922, the Italian fascist dictatorship was established.
During World War II, Italy was first part of the Axis until an armistice with the Allied powers (1940–1943), then a co-belligerent of the
Allies during the Italian resistance and liberation of Italy from German occupation and the collaborationist RSI (1943–1945).
In 1946, the monarchy was replaced by a republic and
the country made a strong recovery.
A developed country with an advanced economy, Italy has the eighth-largest nominal GDP in the world, the second-largest manufacturing sector in
Europe, and plays a significant role in regional and – to a lesser extent – global economic, military, cultural, and political affairs.
It is a founding and leading member of the European Union, and is part of
numerous other international organisations and forums.
As a cultural superpower, Italy has long been a renowned global centre of art, music, literature, cuisine,
fashion, science and technology, and the source of multiple inventions and discoveries.
It has the highest number of World Heritage Sites (61) and is
the fifth-most visited country in the world.